this video is going to tell you about
这部影片将告诉您
the concept of purrito optimality
最优性概念
so far we've thought about some
到目前为止，我们已经考虑过一些
canonical games from game theory and
从博弈论和
we've thought about how to play them but
我们已经考虑过如何玩，但是
we've really been taking the players
我们真的一直在吸引球员
perspective we've been thinking about
我们一直在思考的观点
what what is the right thing to do in a
什么是正确的事情要做
game now I'd like to instead step back
现在我想退后一步
and think about the games from the
并从中考虑游戏
perspective of kind of an outside
外在的观点
observer looking in and trying to judge
观察者，试图判断
what's happening and the question that
发生了什么，问题是
I'd like to ask is is there a sense in
我想问一下
which I can say that some outcomes of a
我可以说，
game are better than other outcomes
游戏胜过其他结果
actually like I'd like to encourage you
其实就像我想鼓励你
to pause the video at this point and
此时暂停视频，然后
just think about this for yourself see
自己想想看
if you can come up with an answer before
如果你能想出一个答案
I tell you what my answer is well let me
我告诉你我的答案很好，让我
give you a bit of a hint um you can't
给你一些提示，你不能
say that one agents interests are more
说一个代理商的利益更大
important than another agents interests
比另一个代理商的利益重要
because I don't know how important the
因为我不知道
different agents are and actually it
实际上是不同的代理商
turns out I can't even say what scales
原来我什至不敢说什么尺度
their utilities are expressed in there
他们的效用在那儿表达
isn't necessarily a common scale for
不一定是
utility between the different agents and
不同代理商之间的效用
so in a sense the the problem of
所以从某种意义上说
evaluating an outcome of a game is kind
评估游戏的结果很友善
of like trying to find the payoff
就像试图找到回报
maximizing outcome when I'm going to be
当我要做的时候最大化结果
paid an amount in different currencies
支付了不同货币的金额
and I don't know what these currencies
我不知道这些货币是什么
are so you can kind of think of the
这样您就可以想到
outcome of a game as an outside observer
游戏作为外部观察者的结果
just interested in kind of social good
只对某种社会公益感兴趣
of the participants as kind of being
参与者的存在
like I'm an outcome where I get pay or
就像我得到报酬的结果
once pay player ones payoff in currency
一次以货币支付玩家的收益
one and I get player two's payoff in
一个，我得到第二个玩家的收益
currency two and nobody can tell me what
货币二，没人能告诉我
the exchange rate is between currency
汇率在货币之间
one and currency two now that I've made
我现在做了一个和第二种货币
this a little bit more concrete let me
这更具体一点让我
again invite you to think about whether
再次邀请您考虑
there's a way that I can identify
有一种我可以识别的方法
outcomes that I would prefer one to
我想要一个的结果
another
另一个
well here's here's a way we can make
好，这是我们可以做的一种方法
this work we can't do it all the time
这项工作我们不能一直做到
but sometimes there's an outcome oh that
但是有时候会有结果哦
is at least as good for everybody
至少对每个人都一样
as some other outcome Oh prime remember
作为其他结果哦，主要记得
an outcome is like a cell of the matrix
结果就像矩阵的一个单元
game so I've got this matrix game and
游戏，所以我有这个矩阵游戏，
there's some outcome Oh which is at
会有一些结果哦
least as good for everybody as some
至少对每个人都一样
other outcome Oh Prime and furthermore
其他结果哦总理和此外
there's some agent who strictly prefers
有些经纪人严格喜欢
Oh to Oprah well in that case I should
噢，那对奥普拉我应该
be so so they let me actually make an
是这样，所以他们让我实际上
example of this so Oh might be that
这样的例子，哦可能是
player one gets seven units of utility
玩家一获得七个单位的效用
and player two gets eight and Oh prime
玩家二获得八，素数
might be that player one gets seven
可能是一名选手获得了七分
units of utility and player two gets two
效用和玩家两个获得两个
units of utility in this case oh is at
在这种情况下，实用单位是
least as good for everybody and it's
至少对每个人都一样，这是
because it's equal for player one and
因为这对玩家一是平等的
it's strictly better for somebody it's
绝对对某人更好
strictly better for player two so in
严格来说对第二个玩家更好
this case it seems reasonable to say
这种情况下似乎可以说合理
that an outside observer should feel
外部观察者应该感觉到的
that outcome oh is better than outcome
那个结果比结果好
Oprah and technically the way we say
奥普拉（Oprah）以及我们所说的方式
this is that outcome Oh purrito
这就是那个结果哦purrito
dominates Oh prime well now I can define
我现在可以定义主宰哦
this concept of Pareto optimality an
帕累托最优的概念
outcome Oh star is purrito optimal if it
结果如果它是星形的，那么星形是最优的
isn't purrito dominated by anything so
并不是purrito主导任何事情
but that's kind of a hard definition
但这有点很难定义
because it's defined in negative terms
因为它是负面定义
let me say it again an outcome Oh star
让我再说一遍结果哦，明星
is pretty optimistic and so let's test
非常乐观，所以让我们测试
our understanding of this definition by
我们对这个定义的理解是
asking a couple of questions
问几个问题
is it possible for a game to have more
游戏是否有可能拥有更多
than one Pareto optimal outcome as
比一个帕累托最优结果
always let me encourage you to think
总是让我鼓励你思考
about this for a second before I answer
在我回答之前大约一秒钟
it of course it is because it's possible
当然是因为有可能
for two outcomes
有两个结果
- neither predominate each other if for
-两者都不占优势
example all payoffs in the game are the
例如游戏中的所有收益都是
same if I have a game where everyone
如果我有一个游戏，每个人都一样
gets a payoff of one no matter what
无论如何都会得到回报
happens then
然后发生
nothing dominates anything else because
没有什么能统治其他任何事情，因为
domination requires somebody to strictly
统治需要有人严格
prefer something to something else so
偏爱其他东西，所以
this game has more than one pretty
这个游戏有多个
optimal outcome something else I can ask
最佳结果我还有其他要求
is does every game have at least one
每个游戏至少都有一个
Pareto optimal outcome or is it possible
帕累托最优结果或是否可能
that just nothing will be fredo optimal
没有什么是最佳的
well well let you think about it for a
好吧，让你考虑一下
second but the answer is yes every game
第二，但答案是每场比赛都是
has to have at least one Pareto optimal
必须至少有一个帕累托最优
outcome this is easy to see because in
结果很容易看到，因为
order for something to not be pre to
命令某事不被pre
optimal it has to be dominated by
最佳，它必须由
something else so in order for there to
所以别的东西，以便在那里
be no pre to optimal outcomes in a game
不能在游戏中获得最佳结果
we would need to have a cycle in pre
我们需要先进行一个循环
dough dominance we would need to have it
面团主导地位，我们需要拥有它
be the case that everything is preload
一切都是预载的情况
dominated by something different and
以不同的东西为主
it's pretty easy to persuade yourself
说服自己很容易
that we can't have cycles with Pareto
我们无法与帕累托有周期
dominance the reason we can't have
主导我们无法拥有的原因
cycles is just the way the period of
周期只是周期的方式
dominance is defined that in order for
主导地位的定义是为了
something to be pretty to dominate it
漂亮的东西来统治它
has to be at least as good for everybody
必须至少对每个人都一样
and strictly preferred by somebody and
并被某人严格首选
I'll leave this to you to think about
我留给你考虑
but but that definition implies that
但是这个定义意味着
there can't be cycles in the period or
该期间不能有周期，或者
dominance relationship so finally let's
优势关系，所以最后让我们
look at our example games that we've
看一下我们的示例游戏
thought about and identify preeto
考虑并确定先例
optimal outcomes and in each case I
最佳结果，在每种情况下我
won't say this every time but I
我不会每次都这样说
encourage you to pause the video when
鼓励您在以下情况下暂停视频
I've put up a game think for yourself
我已经为自己准备了一个游戏
about what the pre doe optimal outcomes
关于事前最佳结果
are and then I'll identify them for you
是，然后我会为您识别它们
so first of all we have
所以首先我们有
coordination game and here these two
协调游戏，这两个
outcomes are both pretty optimal in the
结果在
battle of the sexes game these two
两性游戏之战
outcomes again are pre to optimal the
结果再次是最佳的
change in payoffs here doesn't doesn't
回报的变化这里不是
make a difference in the matching
在匹配中有所作为
pennies game this one's a bit trickier
便士游戏，这个有点棘手
I'll let you think about it for a minute
我让你考虑一下
every outcome is pre to optimal because
每个结果都是最优的，因为
there's no pair of outcomes where
没有一对结果
everybody likes them equal likes the two
每个人都喜欢他们，平等地喜欢两个
outcomes equally well there's always
结果同样好，总有
kind of a strict trade-off that happens
发生一种严格的权衡
because the game is zero-sum and this is
因为游戏是零和，这是
generally true of zero-sum games that
零和游戏通常适用于
every outcome in a zero-sum game is
零和博弈中的每个结果都是
going to be pretty optimal finally here
最终将变得非常理想
we have the prisoner's dilemma game and
我们有囚犯的困境游戏，
let me also let you think about this one
让我也让你考虑一下
turns out here all but one outcome is
事实证明，除了一个结果是
Preto optimal this outcome is not pretty
Preto最优，这种结果并不理想
optimal because it is pretty dominated
最佳，因为它相当主导
by this outcome and now I'm ready to
通过这个结果，现在我准备好了
give you a punchline that we've been
给你一个我们已经
building to for a while about the
建造一段时间
prisoner's dilemma game here's why the
囚徒困境游戏，这就是为什么
prisoner's dilemma is such a dilemma the
囚徒困境就是这样的困境
Nash equilibrium of the prisoner's
纳什均衡的囚犯
dilemma is which in fact is a Nash
困境实际上是纳什
equilibrium in dominant strategies so
优势策略中的均衡
it's the strongest kind of Nash
这是最强的纳什
equilibrium there is then that there's a
平衡，那么有一个
Nash equilibrium in this game in fact
纳什均衡实际上在这个游戏中
everybody should play this equilibrium
每个人都应该发挥这种平衡
even without thinking about even without
即使没有考虑
knowing what the other person is going
知道对方在做什么
to do I can be sure that I should play
我可以确定我应该玩
my strict dominant strategy in this game
我在这场比赛中的严格统治策略
get to this outcome and that is the only
得到这个结果，那是唯一的
non Pareto optimal outcome in this game
此游戏中的非帕累托最优结果
so almost everything in this game is
所以这个游戏中几乎所有的东西都是
kind of good from a social perspective
从社会的角度看是一种善
and the only other thing in the game is
而游戏中唯一的另一件事是
the thing that we strongly predict ought
我们强烈预测的事情应该
to
至
so that's why we think the prisoner's
这就是为什么我们认为囚犯的
dilemma is such a dilemma
困境就是这样的困境